<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/categories/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy is a Means, Not an End</title>
      <link>/2020/10/11/democracy-is-a-means-not-an-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/11/democracy-is-a-means-not-an-end/</guid>
      <description>很好，破除了对民主所有的幻觉
 Author: Michael Munger Source Everyone loves democracy. Ask an American if there is a better form of government, and they’ll be insulted. You believe in democracy, don’t you? And what exactly is it that you believe in? What people mean by “democracy” is some vague combination of good government, protection of individual rights, extremely broad political participation, and widely shared economic prosperity. One might as well throw in an ideal body mass index and a great latke recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obama’s shameful Afghanistan retreat</title>
      <link>/2020/10/11/obama-s-shameful-afghanistan-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/11/obama-s-shameful-afghanistan-retreat/</guid>
      <description>Obama’s shameful Afghanistan retreat: This will embolden the Taliban, Al Qaeda and ISIS
  从阿富汗的耻辱撤退
 Author: Frederick Kagan Source The headlines should read: &amp;ldquo;Obama to slash U.S. troops in Afghanistan by over 40% weeks before he hands over responsibility to a new President.&amp;rdquo; Instead they say: &amp;ldquo;Obama extends U.S. military presence in Afghanistan.&amp;rdquo; Talk about controlling the narrative.
We&#39;re missing the plot here. The President announced on Thursday the most irresponsible decision he could have made about Afghanistan — second only to the promise he had made earlier to pull almost all U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Suffrage Was A Mistake</title>
      <link>/2020/10/11/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/11/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>Author: CHAUNCEY TINKER Source  Part one of a two part series questioning universal suffrage.
 The concept and application of universal suffrage, one person one vote, is actually a relatively recent phenomenon in human history. In this post I will be explaining why I believe universal suffrage has been a factor in the decline of “Western” civilization. I will be referring specifically to the experience of the UK, but I believe the trends are in fact common to most “Western” countries, which have followed a similar course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>