<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>China’s economy is overestimated</title>
      <link>/2020/09/17/china-s-economy-is-overestimated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/17/china-s-economy-is-overestimated/</guid>
      <description>Source: https://www.ft.com/content/961b4b32-3fce-11e9-b896-fe36ec32aece
China’s economy is 12% smaller than official data say, study finds
 Beijing statisticians ‘do not have capacity’ to correct inflated local figures
 China’s economy is about 12 per cent smaller than official figures indicate, and its real growth has been overstated by about 2 percentage points annually in recent years, according to research.
The findings in the paper published on Thursday by the Brookings Institution, a Washington think-tank, reinforced longstanding scepticism about Chinese official statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Halo Effect</title>
      <link>/2020/09/17/the-halo-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/17/the-halo-effect/</guid>
      <description>Delusion One: The Halo Effect  The tendency to look at a company’s overall performance and make attributions about its culture, leadership, values, and more. In fact, many things we commonly claim drive company performance are simply attributions based on prior performance.
  Delusion Two: “The Delusion of Correlation and Causality”  “Two things may be correlated, but we may not know which one causes which. Does employee satisfaction lead to high performance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blueprint for Success</title>
      <link>/2020/09/06/a-blueprint-for-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/06/a-blueprint-for-success/</guid>
      <description>Author: Jim Donovan
Source: UVMazazine, https://uvamagazine.org/articles/a_blueprint_for_success/
After two degrees from MIT, one from Harvard, a couple decades in the business world and a semester teaching at UVA Law, I certainly don’t claim to know everything. But I do have some insight into how to best utilize your assets and how to make the most of your education to succeed in the workplace. For those of you embarking on the journey, maybe my thoughts will help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Basics</title>
      <link>/2020/08/04/business-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/04/business-basics/</guid>
      <description> Business Basics Mindmap
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>