<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: How Market Works</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-how-market-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-how-market-works/</guid>
      <description>The Market Forces of Supply and Demand Economists use the model of supply and demand to analyze competitive markets. In a competitive market, there are many buyers and sellers, each of whom has little or no influence on the market price.
1. The Demand Curve The demand curve shows how the quantity of a good demanded depends on the price. According to the law of demand, as the price of a good falls, the quantity demanded rises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Markets and Welfare</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</guid>
      <description>Consumers, Producers, and the Efficiency of Markets 1. Consumer Surplus Consumer surplus equals buyers’ willingness to pay for a good minus the amount they actually pay, and it measures the benefit buyers get from participating in a market. Consumer surplus can be computed by finding the area below the demand curve and above the price.
 2. Producer Surplus Producer surplus equals the amount sellers receive for their goods minus their costs of production, and it measures the benefit sellers get from participating in a market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: The Economics of the Public Sector</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-the-economics-of-the-public-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-the-economics-of-the-public-sector/</guid>
      <description>Externalities When a transaction between a buyer and seller directly affects a third party, the effect is called an externality. If an activity yields negative externalities, such as pollution, the socially optimal quantity in a market is less than the equilibrium quantity. If an activity yields positive externalities, such as technology spillovers, the socially optimal quantity is greater than the equilibrium quantity.
Governments pursue various policies to remedy the inefficiencies caused by externalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firm Behavior and the Organization of Industry</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/firm-behavior-and-the-organization-of-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/firm-behavior-and-the-organization-of-industry/</guid>
      <description>The Costs of Production The goal of firms is to maximize profit, which equals total revenue minus total cost.
When analyzing a firm’s behavior, it is important to include all the opportunity costs of production. Some of the opportunity costs, such as the wages a firm pays its workers, are explicit. Other opportunity costs, such as the wages the firm owner gives up by working at the firm rather than taking another job, are implicit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Introduction</title>
      <link>/2020/03/12/economics-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/12/economics-introduction/</guid>
      <description>When I started learning economics, I thought economics can teach me to make more money because the word ‘economics’ implied money in my first look. Undoubtablely, my thought is wrong. Therefore, when I decide to write the introduction article, I need to illustrate what is economics indeed.
Accrording to The Principle of Economics by Gregory Mankiw. Economics is the study of how society manages its scarce resources. Economists study how people make decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>