<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welfare on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/welfare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welfare on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/welfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying the price for breakdown of the country&#39;s bourgeois culture</title>
      <link>/2020/10/12/paying-the-price-for-breakdown-of-the-country-s-bourgeois-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/12/paying-the-price-for-breakdown-of-the-country-s-bourgeois-culture/</guid>
      <description>Author: Amy Wax; Larry Alexander Source Video Too few Americans are qualified for the jobs available. Male working-age labor-force participation is at Depression-era lows. Opioid abuse is widespread. Homicidal violence plagues inner cities. Almost half of all children are born out of wedlock, and even more are raised by single mothers. Many college students lack basic skills, and high school students rank below those from two dozen other countries.
The causes of these phenomena are multiple and complex, but implicated in these and other maladies is the breakdown of the country&#39;s bourgeois culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Suffrage Was A Mistake</title>
      <link>/2020/10/11/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/11/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>Author: CHAUNCEY TINKER Source  Part one of a two part series questioning universal suffrage.
 The concept and application of universal suffrage, one person one vote, is actually a relatively recent phenomenon in human history. In this post I will be explaining why I believe universal suffrage has been a factor in the decline of “Western” civilization. I will be referring specifically to the experience of the UK, but I believe the trends are in fact common to most “Western” countries, which have followed a similar course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Markets and Welfare</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</guid>
      <description>Consumers, Producers, and the Efficiency of Markets 1. Consumer Surplus Consumer surplus equals buyers’ willingness to pay for a good minus the amount they actually pay, and it measures the benefit buyers get from participating in a market. Consumer surplus can be computed by finding the area below the demand curve and above the price.
 2. Producer Surplus Producer surplus equals the amount sellers receive for their goods minus their costs of production, and it measures the benefit sellers get from participating in a market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>