<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: How Market Works</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-how-market-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-how-market-works/</guid>
      <description>The Market Forces of Supply and Demand Economists use the model of supply and demand to analyze competitive markets. In a competitive market, there are many buyers and sellers, each of whom has little or no influence on the market price.
1. The Demand Curve The demand curve shows how the quantity of a good demanded depends on the price. According to the law of demand, as the price of a good falls, the quantity demanded rises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Markets and Welfare</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/economics-markets-and-welfare/</guid>
      <description>Consumers, Producers, and the Efficiency of Markets 1. Consumer Surplus Consumer surplus equals buyers’ willingness to pay for a good minus the amount they actually pay, and it measures the benefit buyers get from participating in a market. Consumer surplus can be computed by finding the area below the demand curve and above the price.
 2. Producer Surplus Producer surplus equals the amount sellers receive for their goods minus their costs of production, and it measures the benefit sellers get from participating in a market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>人生戒条 2020-3</title>
      <link>/2020/03/13/2020-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/13/2020-3/</guid>
      <description> 无论是短期还是长期，都不要做损害现金流的事情
 不要往人多的地方挤，别跟风随大流，别听风就是雨
 别打肿脸充胖子
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Introduction</title>
      <link>/2020/03/12/economics-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/12/economics-introduction/</guid>
      <description>When I started learning economics, I thought economics can teach me to make more money because the word ‘economics’ implied money in my first look. Undoubtablely, my thought is wrong. Therefore, when I decide to write the introduction article, I need to illustrate what is economics indeed.
Accrording to The Principle of Economics by Gregory Mankiw. Economics is the study of how society manages its scarce resources. Economists study how people make decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Inference and Decision Theory 2</title>
      <link>/2020/03/02/bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/02/bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory-2/</guid>
      <description>Unit 2: Random Variables, Parametric Models, and Inference from Observation  Random Variable and Distribution Functions A random variable is a function from the sample space Ω to a set of outcomes.
 Cumulative distribution function (cdf) - Value of cdf at \(x\) is probability that the random variable is less than or equal to \(x\).
 Probability mass function (pmf) - Maps each possible value of a discrete random variable to its probability</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Inference and Decision Theory 3</title>
      <link>/2020/03/02/bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/02/bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory-3/</guid>
      <description>Unit 3: Bayesian Inference with Conjugate Pairs: Single Parameter Models  Canonical Statistical Inference Problem Given: data set of \(N\) observations \(X_1, …, X_N\)
 Assume: \(X_i\) are a random (iid) sample from a probability distribution with unknown parameters.
   \(X_i\) and paremeters can be univariate or multivariate
 Set of possible values for \(X\) and/or parameters can be finite, discrete infinite, or continuous
 This unit considers univariate, continuous parameters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Tour of Bayesian Inference and Decision Theory</title>
      <link>/2020/01/31/a-brief-tour-of-bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/31/a-brief-tour-of-bayesian-inference-and-decision-theory/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Bayesians view inference as belief dynamics. It uses evidence to update prior belief to posterior beliefs which serve as prior beliefs for future evidence.
Decision theory is a formal theory of decision making under uncertainty. A decision problem consists of three parts:
Possible actions \(a\) States of the world \(s\) Possible consequences \(c\)  The question is “what is the best action or decision?”
If I want to answer the question, I need to measure the “goodness” of consequences with the \(utility\) function \(u\), and likelihood of states with probability distribution \(p\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accounting Foundations</title>
      <link>/2020/01/19/accounting-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/19/accounting-foundations/</guid>
      <description>1. What is Accounting? What exactly is accounting? First, it is quantitative, it is numbers. Accounting is all about numbers. Second, accounting is financial in nature. Third, accounting is meant to be useful. The fundamental purpose of accounting is to be useful. Accounting is a very practical field of study. Fourth, accounting is useful for making decisions. Accounting helps you use information from the past to make decisions in the present to change the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essentials of Python</title>
      <link>/2020/01/12/the-essentials-of-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/12/the-essentials-of-python/</guid>
      <description>1. About Python 3 Python is a modern, object-oriented scripting language. There’s a core philosophy behind the Python language, which includes the following statements: Beautiful is better than ugly. It’s always a good idea to make your code elegant and readable. Explicit is better than implicit. Don’t make your readers guess what your code does, make it obvious. Simple is better than complex. If you can make it simple, do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamentals of Programming</title>
      <link>/2020/01/09/the-fundamentals-of-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/09/the-fundamentals-of-programming/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Now more than ever, you hear about the importance of STEM education and the need for qualified computer programmers. This article is designed for you, someone who’s curious to pull back the curtains and explore the world of computer programming. I’ll walk you through your first line of code, explain the core concepts needed to write useful programs, and take a peek at several programming languages along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUPPLEMENT TO CHAPTER 1 THE THEORY OF NUMBERS</title>
      <link>/2020/01/07/supplement-to-chapter-1-the-theory-of-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/07/supplement-to-chapter-1-the-theory-of-numbers/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION The integers have gradually lost their association with superstition and mysticism, but their interest for mathematicians has never waned. Gauss, the foremost mathematician of modern times, who devoted himself to many different branches of mathematics, is said to have expressed his opinion of number theory in the remark, “Mathematics is the queen of the sciences and the theory of numbers is the queen of mathematics.”
 1. THE PRIME NUMBERS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Shortcuts For Mac Users</title>
      <link>/2020/01/03/hidden-shortcuts-for-mac-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/03/hidden-shortcuts-for-mac-users/</guid>
      <description>  Command-Z: Undo the previous command
 Shift-Command-Z: Redo
 Command-E: Eject the selected disk or volume
 Shift–C: Open the Computer window
 Command-Control-D: Look up a word in dictionary
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: R for Data Science</title>
      <link>/2020/01/02/book-review-r-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/02/book-review-r-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>After reading the book: R for Data Science, I plan to write a book review to summary some important skills I learned from the book and shed new light on the future study direction. The book helps me understand the whole diagram about data science, and what role R plays in the diagram. However, the book is not a definitive guide. These are a lot of important topics, such as TensorFlow, model building and non-rectangular data, not appearing in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 - THE NATURAL NUMBER (2)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/31/chapter-1-the-natural-number-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/31/chapter-1-the-natural-number-2/</guid>
      <description>THE INFINITUDE OF THE NUMBER SYSTEM. MATHEMATICAL INDUCTION 1. The Principle of Mathematical Induction For any interger \(n\) has been reached we may write the next integer, \(n+1\). We express this property of the sequence of integers by saying that there are \(infinitely\) many integers. The sequence of integers represents the simplest and most natural example of the mathematical infinite, which plays a dominant role in modern mathematics. The step by step procedure of passing from \(n\) to \(n+1\) which generates the infinite sequence of integers also forms the basis of one of the most fundamental patterns of mathematical reasoning, the principle of mathematical induction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 - THE NATURAL NUMBER (1)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/30/the-natural-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/30/the-natural-number/</guid>
      <description>TOC:
INTRODUCTION
CALCULATION WITH INTEGERS
-1.Laws of Arithmetic
-2.The Representation of Integers
-3.Computation in Systems Other than the Decimal
INTRODUCTION Number is the basis of modern mathematics. But what is number? What does it mean to say that \(\frac{1}{2}+\frac{1}{2}=1\), \(\frac{1}{2} \cdot \frac{1}{2}=\frac{1}{4}\), and \((-1)(-1)=1\)? We learned in school the mechanics of fractions and negative numbers, but for a real understanding of the number system we must go back to simpler elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHAT IS MATHEMATICS?</title>
      <link>/2019/12/24/what-is-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/24/what-is-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>Author: Richard Courant &amp;amp; Herbert Robbins
Translator: Guanghua Mao
Source: WHAT IS MATHEMATICS (2nd Edition)
什么是数学 Mathematics as an expression of the human mind reflects the active will, the contemplative reason, and the desire for aesthetic perfection. Its basic elements are logic and intuition, analysis and construction, generality and individuality. Though different traditions may emphasize different aspects, it is only the interplay of these antithetic forces and the struggle for their synthesis that constitute the life, usefulness, and supreme value of mathematical science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Guanghua Mao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good News Is Unplanned</title>
      <link>/2019/12/23/good-news-is-unplanned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/23/good-news-is-unplanned/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ronald Bailey
Translator: Guanghua Mao
Source: Reason, https://reason.com/archives/2015/10/30/good-news-is-unplanned
好事无需规划 Incremental, bottom-up, trial-and-error innovation yields moral progress, superior technologies, and greater wealth. Top-down mandates from centralized authorities are more likely to produce ethical disasters, technological stagnation, and persistent poverty. “Bad news is man-made, top-down, purposed stuff, imposed on history,” Matt Ridley writes in The Evolution of Everything. “Good news is accidental, unplanned, emergent stuff that gradually evolves.”
缓慢演进的、自下而上的、试错式的创新，产生了道德的进步、先进的技术和更多的财富。来自中央权威、自上而下的命令，更容易造成道德灾难、技术停滞和持续贫穷。“坏事都是人为的、自上而下的、刻意设计、故意强加给历史的东西，” Matt Ridley在《万物之进化》中写道。“好事都是意外的、未经计划的、缓慢演化的偶然事件。”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>