<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labor on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/labor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labor on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/labor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything has a diminishing marginal utility</title>
      <link>/2020/08/13/everything-has-a-diminishing-marginal-utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/13/everything-has-a-diminishing-marginal-utility/</guid>
      <description>As an popular economic concept, diminishing marginal utility is not new. We all know that utility deriving from a product or commodity reduces as more and more we consume of it.
The utility, here, can be defined as a level of satisfaction that we get from a consumption of a commodity. On the contrary it can be defined as lack of desire to consume more of it.
When I look back to the history of competence, I surprisingly find out that almost everything has a diminishing marginal utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics: Labor Markets</title>
      <link>/2020/03/14/economics-labor-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/14/economics-labor-markets/</guid>
      <description>The Markets for the Factors of Production The economy’s income is distributed in the markets for the factors of production. The three most important factors of production are labor, land, and capital.
The demand for factors, such as labor, is a derived demand that comes from firms that use the factors to produce goods and services. Competitive, profitmaximizing firms hire each factor up to the point at which the value of the factor’s marginal product equals its price.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>