<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>美利坚治世的终结</title>
      <link>/2020/10/09/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/09/1/</guid>
      <description>2014年克里米亚事件的发生，让众多依靠美利坚的军事力量确保其安全的国家大为失望。川普上台以来，美军从德国、叙利亚、阿富汗不断撤军，而叙利亚的动荡和阿富汗的恐怖主义并没被彻底解决干净。美利坚在不断地抛弃依仗他的盟友。那些地区强国也终于不再韬光养晦。不断挑起战争，介入地区冲突。2020年亚美尼亚和阿塞拜疆开战，背后有着俄罗斯和土耳其势力的支持。亚美尼亚的总理在2018年是依靠美国的支持上台的。但在2020的冲突中，我们并没有看到美国对这个小兄弟生出援手。这四个国家最终竟然是在俄罗斯做出了最后的妥协。
虽然我个人对美利坚彻底退回孤立主义毫无意见，在看了一些报道之后甚至还有些反感那些呼吁美利坚主动出兵的。毫无疑问，对某些极其危险的势力进行打击是绝对有必要的，如二战时期的日本、德国，冷战时期的苏联，以及到处搞恐怖主义的塔利班。但在很多地方，美利坚的干预是没有太大的价值的，比较典型的就是高加索地区、阿拉伯地区、更不需要说南美和非洲, 在这些国家，美利坚投入了不小的财力和兵力但并没有什么效果。这种吃力不讨好的干预完全没有必要。
但如果没有美利坚不遗余力的推行他的制度、价值观，非盎格鲁撒克逊的国家极有可能会慢慢抛弃对财产权的保护、对自由市场的支持、对人基本权利的尊重，一个充满悲剧和杀戮的时代可能会就此开始。
ISIS的崛起、高加索冲突、欧洲难民危机一个动荡时代正在出现。那些年轻人口很多、但是经济不断下行的国家会率先出现危机，与周边各个国家发生冲突和摩擦。在历史学家回顾2020年的时候，估计会把这一年视为美利坚治世的终结吧。更让人失望的是，美利坚自己也出了很多问题&amp;mdash;福利主义、最低工资、分拆大公司、身份政治、民粹主义，改革开放之后那个波澜壮阔、激动人心的时代就要结束了。人们又要过上苦日子了。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Economic Mess in Texas</title>
      <link>/2020/09/28/no-economic-mess-in-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/28/no-economic-mess-in-texas/</guid>
      <description>德州经济安然无恙 Author: Wall Street Journal Source Abstract Last week&#39;s &amp;ldquo;beige book&amp;rdquo; release from the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas shows that despite the struggling oil and gas industry, the Texas economy is still enjoying moderate growth. Since prices in the oil patch began sliding a year ago, pundits on the political left have been waiting for evidence to declare the Texas model a failure.
 Full Text A funny thing has happened to the economic miracle in Texas that liberals predicted would go bust along with oil prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Suffrage Was A Mistake</title>
      <link>/2020/09/19/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/19/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>Author: Chauncey Tinker Source Part one of a two part series questioning universal suffrage. The concept and application of universal suffrage, one person one vote, is actually a relatively recent phenomenon in human history. In this post I will be explaining why I believe universal suffrage has been a factor in the decline of “Western” civilization. I will be referring specifically to the experience of the UK, but I believe the trends are in fact common to most “Western” countries, which have followed a similar course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America The Weird</title>
      <link>/2020/09/17/america-the-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/17/america-the-weird/</guid>
      <description>Author: Victor Davis Hanson  Source: https://www.hoover.org/research/america-weird On first glance, America does not seem that exceptional. Like China and Russia, it is a superpower. And, also like those countries, it is huge territorially. It shares many affinities with Europe. And, like China, Japan and Germany, the United States is an economic powerhouse. And yet, it is a nation unlike any in the world.
In general, outside the West, few of the seven billion people alive today enjoy human rights and the protection of property.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>