<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Suffrage Was A Mistake</title>
      <link>/2020/09/19/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/19/universal-suffrage-was-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>Author: Chauncey Tinker Source Part one of a two part series questioning universal suffrage. The concept and application of universal suffrage, one person one vote, is actually a relatively recent phenomenon in human history. In this post I will be explaining why I believe universal suffrage has been a factor in the decline of “Western” civilization. I will be referring specifically to the experience of the UK, but I believe the trends are in fact common to most “Western” countries, which have followed a similar course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America The Weird</title>
      <link>/2020/09/17/america-the-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/17/america-the-weird/</guid>
      <description>Author: Victor Davis Hanson  Source: https://www.hoover.org/research/america-weird On first glance, America does not seem that exceptional. Like China and Russia, it is a superpower. And, also like those countries, it is huge territorially. It shares many affinities with Europe. And, like China, Japan and Germany, the United States is an economic powerhouse. And yet, it is a nation unlike any in the world.
In general, outside the West, few of the seven billion people alive today enjoy human rights and the protection of property.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>