<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Be the Best Gold Digger You Can Be</title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/be-the-best-gold-digger-you-can-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/be-the-best-gold-digger-you-can-be/</guid>
      <description>Author: Jen Kim  Source  Does nature’s get-rich-quick scheme really pay?
 There was a time when the label of “gold digger” was a stigma or something to be ashamed of. “She/he is a gold digger,” you would warn your pal. Nowadays, it seems dating or marrying for money is not only out in the open, but also touted as something to be proud of.
Bravo’s Matchmaker Millionaire, (which I confess, I love) is the perfect example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wealthier you get, the less social you are. </title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/the-wealthier-you-get-the-less-social-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/the-wealthier-you-get-the-less-social-you-are/</guid>
      <description>Author: Josh Rosenbl  Source: https://www.vox.com/2016/5/5/11578994/income-friends-family Rich Americans aren’t only getting richer. They’re becoming more isolated from the rest of America, too.
A recent analysis of survey data from more than 100,000 Americans finds that the rich spend significantly less time socializing than low-income Americans. On average, they spend 6.4 fewer evenings per year in social situations.
Rich Americans spend less time socializing with their family and neighbors — although they do spend more time socializing with friends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>