<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NUMBERS on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/numbers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NUMBERS on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/numbers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SUPPLEMENT TO CHAPTER 1 THE THEORY OF NUMBERS</title>
      <link>/2020/01/07/supplement-to-chapter-1-the-theory-of-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/07/supplement-to-chapter-1-the-theory-of-numbers/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION The integers have gradually lost their association with superstition and mysticism, but their interest for mathematicians has never waned. Gauss, the foremost mathematician of modern times, who devoted himself to many different branches of mathematics, is said to have expressed his opinion of number theory in the remark, “Mathematics is the queen of the sciences and the theory of numbers is the queen of mathematics.”
 1. THE PRIME NUMBERS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 - THE NATURAL NUMBER (2)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/31/chapter-1-the-natural-number-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/31/chapter-1-the-natural-number-2/</guid>
      <description>THE INFINITUDE OF THE NUMBER SYSTEM. MATHEMATICAL INDUCTION 1. The Principle of Mathematical Induction For any interger \(n\) has been reached we may write the next integer, \(n+1\). We express this property of the sequence of integers by saying that there are \(infinitely\) many integers. The sequence of integers represents the simplest and most natural example of the mathematical infinite, which plays a dominant role in modern mathematics. The step by step procedure of passing from \(n\) to \(n+1\) which generates the infinite sequence of integers also forms the basis of one of the most fundamental patterns of mathematical reasoning, the principle of mathematical induction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 - THE NATURAL NUMBER (1)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/30/the-natural-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/30/the-natural-number/</guid>
      <description>TOC:
INTRODUCTION
CALCULATION WITH INTEGERS
-1.Laws of Arithmetic
-2.The Representation of Integers
-3.Computation in Systems Other than the Decimal
INTRODUCTION Number is the basis of modern mathematics. But what is number? What does it mean to say that \(\frac{1}{2}+\frac{1}{2}=1\), \(\frac{1}{2} \cdot \frac{1}{2}=\frac{1}{4}\), and \((-1)(-1)=1\)? We learned in school the mechanics of fractions and negative numbers, but for a real understanding of the number system we must go back to simpler elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>