<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Guanghua Mao&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Basics</title>
      <link>/2020/08/04/business-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/04/business-basics/</guid>
      <description> Business Basics Mindmap
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Management Essentials</title>
      <link>/2020/04/15/database-management-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/15/database-management-essentials/</guid>
      <description>1. Database System Good decisions require good information derived from raw facts. Users can manage data efficiently when it is stored in database in term of size, security, accuracy, ease of updating and redundance.
Databases are shared, integrated computer structure that stores a collection of data.
 End-user data: raw facts of interest to the end user
 Metadata: data about data, description of data characteristics and relationships in data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essentials of Python</title>
      <link>/2020/01/12/the-essentials-of-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/12/the-essentials-of-python/</guid>
      <description>1. About Python 3 Python is a modern, object-oriented scripting language. There’s a core philosophy behind the Python language, which includes the following statements: Beautiful is better than ugly. It’s always a good idea to make your code elegant and readable. Explicit is better than implicit. Don’t make your readers guess what your code does, make it obvious. Simple is better than complex. If you can make it simple, do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamentals of Programming</title>
      <link>/2020/01/09/the-fundamentals-of-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/09/the-fundamentals-of-programming/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Now more than ever, you hear about the importance of STEM education and the need for qualified computer programmers. This article is designed for you, someone who’s curious to pull back the curtains and explore the world of computer programming. I’ll walk you through your first line of code, explain the core concepts needed to write useful programs, and take a peek at several programming languages along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>